[Music]
imagine this you're in a 24 hour fitness
in the corner all by yourself your
headphones are on you're focused and
you're getting your bicep curls in
you're having a great workout and then
out of nowhere some jackal comes
sprinting over and says hey I think
you're going a little bit too fast in
your reps you really need to slow down
and let the muscle work more if you go
too fast it doesn't let the muscle work
enough and you start thinking to
yourself oh maybe I've been doing
this all wrong the whole time and then
before you can change anything boom
comes sprinting over a strength
conditioning coach who works at the
middle school soccer players he smashes
that guy over the place to go no no no
no no no ill do everything as fast as
you can you don't want to teach yourself
to be slow there you go oh wait a minute
well if I go too fast I don't work
muscle but if I don't go fast enough I
learn to be slow oh crap what do I do
well good thing you came to this video
today because I'm gonna answer your
question for you the age-old question
what's on the tip of everyone's mind in
America should I do my repetitions as
fast as I possibly can or should I go as
slow kind of really slow down and do 20
30 40 second reps or as long as I can
well if this is anything besides the
first video of mine you've ever seen you
know the answer and so we first have to
ask the question of what's the goal why
are you doing the bicep curl in the
first place what are we training for in
other words what's the outcome we're
looking to get because the real answer
is both of those gentlemen or ladies
were right and both were wrong depends
on the context what are we doing the
curl for and so I'm going to cut
straight to the chase here and tell you
my answers I like to think about
strength auditioning or exercise or
resistance training even more
specifically as giving you kind of six
different at a possible adaptations so
I'm gonna go through each one right now
and tell you whether you should do your
repetitions fast at a normal speed or
intentionally slow well let's start off
with the first one that's what I call
skill development
so imagine you're trying to get better
out of movements a snatch or a vertical
jump or sprint or even a squat for that
matter I think it's actually important
to do some repetitions than all three
different speeds so of course going slow
and make sure you're understanding the
position you're sequencing is proper
your your technique is in the right
place going slow helps they're the same
thing with normal speed of course well
the advantage of also going fast is it
actually is really difficult to mimic
proper movement mechanics all those
other things if you only go slow and
then you actually try to execute them
fast so imagine someone who only
practices squatting at a really slow
speed and then they think they're gonna
be able to replicate those mechanics
when they go really fast when they go
really heavy it's just not gonna happen
you can do all the really slow stepping
mechanics you want when you're trying to
work on someone's moving running speed
but as soon as they then to actually
take off in actual speed oh that's gonna
go to waste and so you do need to
practice speed across your skill
movements across all three speed types
and particularly fast right and as you
gradually improve your speed at say 80
percent then try to go 82 percent notice
you have a technical breakdown okay
great
they try to get better at presenting
slowly get yourself up to space as
possible but don't eliminate fast stuff
even for skill development right so
physical therapists and platic trainers
keep that in mind when you're trying to
improve some as mechanics whether it's
squatting or running or foot position
etc don't forget to ask them to do the
same thing with some speed
the next adaptation speed or power of
remember power is force times velocity
so I'm gonna kind of lump these two in
because it shares a lot of what you
would find in speed development and then
we'll get into force development or
strength in the next one so that one's
pretty obvious in that case do things
that are fast
of course the caveat with here and I
should say this for all the things I'm
talking about is we're assuming you're
doing these things with good technique
so we rarely going to advocate someone
do something at a speed that completely
ruins their positioning or their
mechanics or their technique that's not
we're saying what we're saying is
assuming you can handle at least pretty
good or 90 plus percent or something of
your technique then try to go as fast as
possible if you want to get faster you
have to go fast the other thing I would
actually argue
here and this is in some other videos
that I'll be doing or have done is over
speed training people really forget
about things like that a good example is
a lot of people have done speed work
where they do some Sprint's since they
dragged a sled or a parachute but how
many of you have done the opposite where
you actually use an implement to pull
you and make you go faster than you're
normally capable that's called over
speed training and it's highly highly
effective for speed and power
development okay no real need to go slow
here again if it's a skill issue then
that goes back to the skill but once you
have the skill down if the goal is power
speed there's no real advantage to going
even normal speed or slow try to go fast
for strength you can use a combination
it depends on what you're trying to do
of course strength this is force yeah
and that equals mass times acceleration
so accelerating improves force
production so going fast makes a ton of
sense there but you can also do normal
or slow speed a good example of this
would be paused quat's
or pause deadlifts or pause bench or
pause pull-ups things like that
isometrics require Centrex even slowy
centers require a tremendum a tremendous
amount of force production because
you're having to actually hold things in
different positions so the time and her
tension goes way up you can also load
them a lot heavier than you can
concentrate gazelle so I would say I
would make an argument that you probably
want to hedge your bets and more towards
normal and fast more often but there is
still some times when you could do slow
for strength development hypertrophy is
most of the knoll normal to slow you
don't really need to go as fast as
possible in your repetitions for that
you can do a little bit of it but you're
probably gonna get more bang for your
buck for the normal and the slow for
hypertrophy now you can see my other
videos on the mechanics of hypertrophy
development or the mechanisms rather and
that'll help you understand why right we
need a couple of things to happen in
order to induce hypertrophy and you're
not gonna get those as much by going
really fast with your repetitions for
fat loss
it doesn't matter there's an argument
for all of these things in fact I would
I would really suggest use a combination
check out the physiology of fat loss
videos endurance would be the same thing
right depends on what type of
endurance we're talking about are we
talking about aerobic endurance long
duration endurance an aerobic endurance
high-intensity interval endurance
muscular endurance what are we really
getting at but you can make an example
for all of these things we could do a
squat for example you can build up some
great muscular endurance by doing wall
sits for a minute you could also get
them by doing glute bridges as fast as
you can for a hundred repetitions or
whatever right so we can make an
argument across the board the last one
then kind of the extra adaptation I put
in here for health or overall wellness
you should do a combination for all of
the things I explained right so to me
you'll have to see one of the health
videos but that's really a combination
of speed strength power I portray an
endurance and skill and so if those are
all requisites being healthy then we
need to train across the spectrum of
speeds as well I hope that helped and
we'll catch you next time on five
minutes hopefully a little bit less than
that phys thanks for your support
[Music]
you